# Paweł ADAMCZAK Backend Developer

github.com/pawelad

@ pawel.ad@gmail.com

+48 732 005 766

Kraków, Poland



I'm a backend developer with almost 10 years of professional experience. I enjoy using and creating software that can be called objectively good, or as close to it as possible. I like tasks that are out of my comfort zone and the knowledge that comes with them. I believe that good practices and attention to detail are very important in general, and especially crucial in IT. I think humility and open-mindedness are two of the most important qualities a person can have.

# SKILLS

 ${\bf Programming\ Languages} \quad {\bf Python}, {\tt Go}$ 

**Databases** PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, Elasticsearch

Frameworks Django, Django REST Framework, Flask, FastAPI, Celery, pytest, Bootstrap mypy, Pydantic, httpx, Click, Rich, black, Ruff, Nox, tox, pip-tools, MkDocs Tools Docker, Docker Compose, Terraform, CloudFormation, Ansible, git, zsh AWS, GitHub CI, CircleCI, nginx, dokku, OpenAPI, JSON Schema, Sentry



# EXPERIENCE

# November 2024 August 2018

### Backend Engineer, TWENTY3

Remote / London, UK

- > Integral part of the team that rewrote company's main football data ingestion pipeline, that imports and post-processes thousands of football events every day (from multiple data providers), and exposes them through an internal API.
- > Responsible for productising proof of concepts created by the Data Science team into MVPs.
- > Implemented best practices, including:
  - > Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery pipelines
  - > Docker based development environments
  - > Using JSON Schema for dynamic API documentation
  - Creating company's CloudFormation based laaC stack
  - ➤ Adding Python type hints
  - > Using Pydantic for validating data from all our data providers
  - Using Sentry for error and performance tracking
  - > Centralizing log digestion
- ▶ Helped create tools used by major football clubs, media and betting companies, including SkySports, Squawka, LiveScore and William Hill.

Python PostgreSQL Redis Django Django REST Framework Celery Pydantic AWS ECS CloudFormation Circle Cl Sentry

# July 2018 September 2017

### Platform Developer, VM FARMS

Toronto, Canada

- ➤ Part of a platform engineering team that maintained:
  - > Custom-built deployment pipeline for our clients
  - Client facing portal, that allowed them to configure app environments and trigger new deployments
  - > All-purpose internal CLI for our operations team
- ➤ Worked directly with our in-house operations team to provide them with the tools to efficiently provision, configure and continuously support our client's infrastructure.

Python PostgreSQL MySQL Django Click Terraform Ansible Consul Vault Vagrant AWS

# August 2017 October 2016

### Backend Developer, OMNI DIGITAL

Bristol, UK

1

- ➤ Helped create and maintain internal and public facing projects for clients such as NHS, UK Chamber of Shipping and SWNS.
- > Implemented a company-wide Ansible stack used for all deployments.

Python MySQL Elasticsearch Django Wagtail Ansible Digital Ocean

# September 2016 September 2015

### **Backend Developer, SIDNET SOLUTIONS**

Remote / Warsaw, Poland

- > Created and maintained:
  - Schedoodle, an internal tool that helped track availability of all employees
  - Official Polish site for Kolbe personality tests
  - > Canola trading platform made for one of the biggest Polish oil distributors
- Responsible for releasing and maintaining some of our open source projects on GitHub.

Python PostgreSQL Django Bootstrap Digital Ocean

# September 2015 April 2015

### Backend Developer, JMR TECHNOLOGIES

Warsaw, Poland

- Helped develop and release two of the company's biggest (at the time) Python projects:
  - > Fully multilingual and customisable product knowledge base
  - ➤ Parcel tracking status aggregator that integrated with multiple delivery companies
- Responsible for managing our production server and creating most of our provisioning automation

Python MySQL Elasticsearch Django Fabric



# **EDUCATION**

2013 - 2016 Warsaw University of Technology

2010 - 2013 I Liceum Ogólnokształcące w Zielonej Górze



# **PROJECTS**

#### **PYMONZO**

github.com/pawelad/pymonzo https://pymonzo.pawelad.dev/

Modern Python API client for Monzo public API. Fully type annotated, with explicitly defined and validated API schemas (via Pydantic), sensible defaults, easy authentication (with automatic access token refreshing) and optional Rich support for pretty printing.

Python Pydantic httpx GitHub CI MkDocs Read the Docs

#### MONZ

github.com/pawelad/monz 
https://monz.pawelad.dev/

Simple CLI for quickly accessing your Monzo account. Built on top of pymonzo.

Python Click Rich GitHub CI MkDocs Read the Docs

#### **FAKESTER**

github.com/pawelad/fakester ## https://fakester.pawelad.me/

Rickroll your boss friend while preserving the element of surprise.

Simple Django website that allows creating URL redirects that help fool your <del>boss</del> friend.

Python Django Bootstrap GitHub CI dokku

# MUSIC SNAPSHOT

# github.com/pawelad/music\_snapshot

Save a snapshot of your day as a Spotify playlist. CLI for saving a part of your music listening history (taken from Last.fm) and saving it as a Spotify playlist.

Python Click Rich GitHub CI

# A Z LANGUAGES

INTERESTS

Polish English









- traveling nba
- live music open source
- > photography
- > music making
- tv series
- movies

# **66** References

Michał Wojciechowski CEO, SIDNET SOLUTIONS michal@sidnet.info

### Alexandre Byeon

Principal SRE, PRODIGY EDUCATION tidhilm@gmail.com

### Kyle Joseph

Full Stack Developer, TWENTY3 kyle@seoplay.co.uk

2